SUMMARY

I'm a data scientist specialized in improving business performances through data analysis and sales forecast to find optimal performance criteria for the business to be successful. I have extensive experience in design, implementation, and analysis of data-driven studies/decisions for businesses.

EDUCATION

Springboard May 2020 - Current

This online data science cohort consists of 500+ hours of intensive curriculums in data science, machine learning, Python, and SQL. Including one guided capstone and two selective capstone projects (see projects).

San Jose State University

Summer 2010 - Winter 2012

B.A. Psychology 2012

EMPLOYMENT

Super Cue Cafe, Co-owner, SF and San Mateo

Jan. 2013 - May 2018

Collected data to forecast sales on a weekly basis to help inventory and staffing efficiently. Analyze product sales seasonally to help decide on which products to keep, replace, or promote. Stores staffed according to the forecasts had yearly net gain increasing from 5~20%.

U.S. Army, *92A - Logistical Supply Specialist*, South Korea

June 2003 - June 2006

This is where I trained to be disciplined. I began as a follower, learned teamwork, and developed leadership.

SKILLS

SOFTWARE AND PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES: Python, SQL, MS Excel, MS PowerPoint

DATA ANALYSIS: Pandas, NumPy, statsmodels, Scikit-learn, SciPy

DATA VISUALIZATION: Seaborn, Matplotlib

PREDICTIVE MODELS: ARIMA, SARIMAX, BATS, TBATS, HWE

PROJECTS

Time Series Forecast

Sept. 2020 - Nov. 2020

Using Python to clean and implement data to several time series models. I was able to make a model that's able to forecast sales on a hourly level, and capture three different seasonality: daily, weekly, and yearly.